本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
翻译   米小勒    KIKO    CS小明漫画家    蔡    我叫魏碧慧
翻译   迷失重生教堂   Marshal同学   天启章鱼X    小欠   lottie筱妤
时间轴   太太乐叽叽    SumenQ       后期   小亲斤
校对   米小勒       总监   米小勒
僵 尸
国 度
.
第一季 第六集
《僵尸国度》前情提要
Previously on Z Nation.
这些都是僵尸咬的
Those are zombie bites.
八个僵尸
Eight of them.
在你们面前的是唯一已知的被僵尸咬伤之后
You're looking at the only human known to have survived
还能活下来的人
being bitten by a zombie.
如果我们能把他送到加利福尼亚的实验室
If we can get him to the lab in California
他们就能用他的血造出更多抗体
they can use his blood and make more of the vaccine.
那不会是我认为的那东西吧
Is that what I think?!
不是鲨鱼哟
They ain't sharks!
你还在想他吗
You still think about him?
安托万吗
Antoine?
我试着不去想他
I try not to.
安托万吗
Antoine?
是他吗
Is that him?
不是
No.
当时我都没搞清楚安托万身上发生了什么
Even if I never know for sure what happened to Antoine
我很高兴现在能和你在一起
I'm okay with being here now with you.
我也很高兴
I'm good with that too.
全国现已进入紧急状态
This is a national emergency.
我现在决定汇总一下
I've decided to catalog
目前有关僵尸病毒起源的各类说法
all the theories about where the Z virus came from.
其种类可谓五花八门
There's more than a few.
所以说僵尸是拜火教对死人复活的称呼吗
Is it what the Zoroastrians would call Frashokereti?
还是我们被亚马逊上的脑残洗脑了
Or are we contaminated with Amazon brain rot?
又或许我们的星球被彗星的尾巴扫到
Or maybe we passed through the tail of a comet
将僵尸的灰烬洒落在了地球上
that sprinkled the earth with zombie dust.
还是说这是一种从国防部实验室不幸流出的
Or was it a defense department weaponized virus
生化病毒呢
that escaped the lab?
也可能这是一个
Or how about
本身会成为事实的预言
self fulfilling prophecy.
社会大众都对僵尸为之着迷  然后僵尸
Public fascination with all things zombie just
这一虚幻的预言变成了现实
willed it into existence.
这些说法越往南边传的越离谱
As things went south the theories got weirder.
在世界末日的关头  正是各种宗教布道的大好时机
Good times for religions with an end of the world scenario.
说的越疯狂越精彩
The crazier the better.
有关天启的生意又火了
The Apocalypse business was booming.
至少还能有机会让这门生意火起来
At least while there still was business to boom.
爱尔兰诗人及剧作家  曾获1923年诺贝尔文学奖
这让我想起了叶芝的一首诗
It reminds me of a poem by Yeats.
"于是何等恶兽  它的时辰终于到来
"And what rough beast, its hour come round at last,
懒洋洋地走向伯利恒来投生"
slouches toward Bethlehem to be born?"
无任何解药
There is no cure.
到底是何等恶兽啊
What rough beast indeed.
汉尼拔镇  密苏里州
天父啊  我们请求您守护我们的兄弟姐妹们
Father, we ask that watch over our brothers and sisters
当他们离开教堂的会众  奔向一段更伟大的旅程
as they leave our congregation for a greater journey.
阿门
Amen.
虽然我们此生无缘再会
And although we will not see them again in this life,
但他们依旧会通过他们的牺牲  继续活下去
they will live on through their sacrifice.
现在我请求各位起立
Now I ask you all to rise.
伊莱兄弟  马修兄弟
Brother Eli, Brother Matthew,
请帮一下这几位复生的教友
please help with the Resurrected
让我们虔诚祈祷
Let us pray.
今天是充满喜悦的一天
For today is a day of joy.
宗教仪式上傅油使神圣化
我现在请求为各位受傅者上前一步
I ask now for the anointed to please step forward.
这几位兄弟姐妹
These brothers and sisters
将很快领悟到宁静的真正深意
will soon know the true meaning of peace
而这深意唯有信仰和重生方能授予
that only belief and resurrection can bring.
希望这些能守卫您旅途的安全
May these keep you safe on your journey
并且成为您救助苍生的利器
and serve as the instrument of your salvation.
我羡慕你们  兄弟们
I envy you, brothers.
姐妹
Sister.
让我们鸣钟
Let us ring the bell
然后愉快地召唤更多重生的人们
and joyously call out for more of the resurrected
加入到我们中间来
to join our flock.
伊莱兄弟
Brother Eli.
马修兄弟
Brother Matthew.
请做好迎接他们的准备
Please prepare to greet them.
这附近没有僵尸
No Zs in sight.
还有谁也在担忧着那位"阳光先生"呢
Anybody else worried about Mr. Sunshine out there?
我知道
I know.
看来他的状况每况愈下
He's looking worse.
没错  他一开始就很让人毛骨悚然了
Yeah, he was pretty creepy to start with.
拜托  大家还是让他休息一下吧
Come on, guys. Give him a break.
现在是世界末日  大家状态都不好
It's the Apocalypse. None of us look our best.
就像顶着拖沓的乱发过了一天
It's like one long bad hair day.
说到发型  他的光头是怎么回事
Speaking of hair, what's with all the bald patches?
可能疫苗就相当于僵尸病毒的化疗
Maybe that vaccine is like zombie chemo.
也许疫苗现在已经失效了
Or maybe that vaccine isn't working.
你怎么看  多克
What do you think, Doc?
我见过比他看上去状况更好的僵尸
I've seen Zs look better than him.
他能撑到加州吗
Will he make it to California?
如果可以加快脚步的话
If we haul ass.
如果他变成僵尸  我们只好杀掉他了
If he goes zombie, we might have to put him down.
我投票刺穿他的脑袋
Dibs on piking him.
如果他变异的话  刺穿他还不是小事一桩
If he turns, piking him's the least of our problems.
怎么了
What?
短暂休息结束  我们继续前进
Pit stop's over. Let's get moving.
哥长了个巨型膀胱  不可以吗
I have a ginormous bladder.
有种告我啊
Sue me.
我现在都能拿几个僵尸去做堪萨斯烤肋排了
Man, I sure could use some of them Kansas City barbecue ribs about now.
亲爱的  你也是个肋排(食人)大胃王对吧
How bout you, darlin'. You're a big rib eater, aren't you?
你知道吗  我刚才差一点就开始同情你了
You know I was almost starting to feel sorry for you.
作为一个两天没吃饭的人  你这表情
You look pretty happy for someone who hasn't eaten
也太开心了点
in two days.
这还不算最糟嘛
Could be worse.
真的吗
Really?
至少我们还活着  对吧
We're still alive, aren't we?
你总能看到事情好的一面
You were always a glass half full kinda guy.
我最爱你这点了
It's what I love about you.
其实我很期待能在普罗温斯敦
Actually I'm looking forward to getting some food
找到一些食物  再洗个热水澡
and a hot shower at Provincetown.
别抱太大希望
Well don't get your hopes up.
我们现在都不确定这个地方是否还存在
We don't even know if this place still exists.
哈蒙德在地图上把这里标做成了补给点
Hammond had it marked on his map as a resupply place.
如果他的联系人威廉姆斯正是
And if his contact there is the same Major Williams
我在国民警卫队的威廉姆斯少校
from my National Guard days,
我们还真有可能获得一些帮助
we might actually get some help.
我们现在就依靠一张死人的地图吗
So we're relying on the map of a dead guy?
怕你忘了
In case you forgot
提醒一下  那个人是为了保护你而死的
that dead guy was a hero who died protecting you.
死也不意味着他就可以顺势成为英雄
Just because he's dead doesn't make him a hero.
我真心希望普罗温斯敦还在
Well I hope Provincetown does exist
因为我们现在除了希望  其他一无所有
because we're out of just about everything but hope.
第1554个
One thousand five hundred and fifty four.
进入之前  请准备上缴所有武器
普罗温斯敦  无武器区域
交出所有的武器  他们是认真的吗
Surrender all weapons? Are they serious?
看上去是的
Looks like.
你打算怎么办
What do you wanna do?
入乡随俗
Their town, their rules.
看上去我们没有其他的选择
Looks like we don't have much of a choice.
停  这里是私人领地
Stop right there! This is a private compound.
我要求你们调转车头
I'm gonna have to ask you to turn around
从哪里来的就回哪里去
and go back the way you came.
我们找威廉姆斯少校
I'm looking for Major Wiliams.
乔·威廉姆斯
Joe Williams.
你又是谁
And who are you?
我是查尔斯·加内特中士
I'm Sergeant Charles Garnett,
佐治亚国家警卫队的
Georgia National Guard.
我们从僵尸爆发之前就认识了
We've knowm each other going back pre-z.
在这等着  你的人待在车里
Wait there. Your crew stays in the truck.
他们要是敢出来  或者我看见有人亮武器
They try to get out or we see a weapon,
我就开火
we'll fire.
大家别妄动
Easy everyone.
查理能应付得来
Charlie's got it under control.
矮油  都叫上查理了呦
So you're calling him Charlie now?
没错  你要是不给姐闭嘴
Yeah, and I'm gonna start calling you my bitch
姐就叫你婊子
if you don't shut up.
我的天
Well holy shit.
查理·加内特的鬼魂上门来了
It's the ghost of Charlie Garnett.
我还以为见不到你了  至少活着见不到了
Never expected to see you again. At least not alive.
你好啊  乔  我也没想到能再见到你
Hey, Joe. Didn't expect to see you again either.
看来你我都坚持下来了
Looks like we're both still standing.
看来如此
Looks like.
上次我见到你
Last time I saw you,
你把我从僵尸堆里捞了出来
you were pulling my ass out of a ditch full of Zs.
还你人情罢了
Just returning the favor.
那天我们杀了多少僵尸
How many Zs we kill that day?
还不够多
Not enough.
我能放下手吗
Do you mind?
放下枪
Stand down.
你是我见到的第一个故人
You're the first person I've seen from before.
你怎么混到这来了
How the hell you end up here?
其实我在给政府办件事
I'm actually on a mission for the government,
不管你信不信了
if you can believe that.
如果换了别人说这话
If it was anybody but you,
我还真不信
I wouldn't.
我们从纽约赶过来的  好几天没吃东西了
We've come from New York. Haven't eaten in a few days.
纽约
New York?
这一年多就没见过
Haven't seen anyone
有谁活着从东密西西比过来的
east of the Mississippi for over a year.
你们一共几个人
How many of you are there?
八个  包括一名医生
Eight. Including a doctor.
货真价实的医生吗
Real doctor?
算是吧
Sort of.
他看过好多集《急诊室的故事》
He's watched a lot of E.R.
那好
All right.
进来跟我讲讲你的经历  我们给你弄些吃的
Come inside and tell me your story. We'll get you some food.
但你们的卡车要停在外面
But the truck stays outside.
放行
Let them in.
当然  你们都得上交武器
And of course you'll have to check your weapons.
别忘了还给我们
Just make sure we get these back.
我怎么一点都没觉得安心呢
Why is this not making me feel any safer?
看来这家伙见过场面啊
Looks like it's seen a little action.
以前做过狱警吗
Ex prison guard?
运输安全管理局的
TSA.
就跟《道奇城》[西部片]似的
Just like Dodge City.
我们自有道理
We have our reasons.
做得对
Makes sense.
安检越严
Strong on the outside.
内部才能安全
Safe on the inside.
少校  说了你可能不信
Major, you're not gonna believe this.
三个雅各布的信徒回来了
Three of Jacob's flock are back.
威廉姆斯少校
Major Williams?
我们想回来
We'd like to come back.
我们不该走的
We were wrong to leave.
原来雅各布就是一疯掉的邪教头子
Jacob turned out to be just some crazy cult leader.
我们带吃的回来了
We brought food.
我们该怎么处理他们
What do you want us to do?
检查下他们  没问题就放进来
If they're clean, let 'em back in.
没准还有更多"迷途羔羊"想回来呢
Probably won't be the last of his sheep to wander back.
没有那把锤头  我真是一身轻松
I feel so much lighter without that damn hammer.
我感觉像是在裸奔  整个人都不好了
Yeah, I feel naked, and not in a good way.
一开始  每个人都是全副武装
When we started out, everyone was armed.
一天  有个男人射杀了他妻子的男性朋友
Then one day a guy decided to shoot his wife's boyfriend.
他变异了  结果我们死了5个人
He turned, and we lost five people.
所以我们制定了规定
So we made a rule.
只有警卫能在内部携带武器
Only guards could carry inside.
之后来了个贸易集团  抢走了警卫的枪
Then a trading group came in. Took a gun off a guard.
那时死了7个人  我们庆幸情况没变得更糟
Seven dead that time. We were lucky it wasn't worse.
我们的防线很坚固  从未被攻破
We have a strong perimeter. Never been breached.
问题都出现在内部
All our problems happened inside.
所以我们消除了威胁
So we removed the threats.
这段时间内  内部禁止携带武器
No weapons inside the walls, period.
这样能更好更安全的生活
It's a better way to live. Safer.
整天全副武装对人有影响
Being armed all the time has an effect on people.
也许是我天真  不过这的确带给我希望
Maybe I'm naive, but this gives me hope.
这是关僵尸的笼子吗
Is this a zombie cage?
这些天不怎么用了
Doesn't seem much use these days.
我们每天在附近巡逻两次
We patrol the surrounding area for Zs twice a day,
所以僵尸对我们来说不是问题
so they aren't really a problem.
我们要担心的是人类
It's the people we have to worry about.
自从禁止携带武器以来
Since going weapon-free,
一年多没有出现过死亡事件了
we've gone over a year without a fatality.
想一想  你在外面的世界里
Think about that. You've been out in the world.
过去一年内你目睹过多少死亡事件
How many deaths have you seen in the last year?
够一辈子了
Enough for a lifetime.
如果出现自然死亡又该怎么办呢
What if someone, you know, dies of natural causes?
当然  这有可能发生
Sure, that could happen.
所有门都是自动关闭的
All the doors and gates close automatically,
将院子的每个部分封闭起来  像潜水艇一样
sealing off each section of the compound. Like on a submarine.
僵尸打不开
Can't be opened by Zs.
一切都是防僵尸的
Everything's been zombie-proofed.
你听说过泰坦尼克号没
You ever hear of the Titanic?
欢迎你滚回外面的车上
You're welcome to wait outside in your vehicle.
请原谅我的朋友  他受到不小的刺激
You'll have to forgive my friend. He's been through a lot.
我们也一样
We all have.
没有十全十美的事儿  但我们尽力为之了
Nothing's perfect, but this is as close as it gets.
不久后  大部分人发现
After a while, most people find
他们可以好好的睡上一晚
they can actually sleep through the night.
真的吗  真不敢想象
Really? I can't imagine that.
我们自给自足
We grow all our own fruits and vegetables.
残羹剩饭和垃圾都会进入生物发电机
The scraps and our waste all go into a biomass generator.
我们一天供电4小时
We're up to four hours of electricity a day.
真的吗  好棒
Really? That's cool.
他们什么来头
What's their story?
我们和之前进来的传道士有些矛盾
We had a little trouble a while back with a preacher we took in.
他不可救药了
He drank his own Kool-Aid.
认为僵尸灾变实际是基督再临
Decided the Zompocalypse was actually The Second Coming
我们应该挽救僵尸而不是杀了他们
and we needed to save the Zs, not kill them.
他称僵尸为"重生者"  真是疯子
Calls them "The Resurrected." Real whack-job.
我不是研究《圣经》的专家
I'm not an expert on the Bible,
但我肯定《圣经》中没有提到僵尸
but I'm pretty sure there's nothing in there about zombies.
我们把他和他的追随者都踢了出去
We had to kick him out, along with his followers.
我之前也见过  疯狂的思想传得很快
I've seen this kind of thing before. Crazy spreads fast.
那你为什么让他们回来
So why would you let them back in?
他们有家人在这里
They all had family still here.
我知道一旦他们出去一段时间
I knew once they were out a while,
就会挨饿害怕  一部分人会回来的
they'd get hungry or scared and some would come back.
像发条一样  今天这三人回来了
Like clockwork these three turned up today.
不是真正的信徒哦
Not true believers, huh?
肚子空空能去信谁
Hard to believe on an empty stomach.
说到这  让你的人吃点东西吧
Speaking of which, let's get you people something to eat.
第一餐我请客  之后就得交易了
First meal is on me. The rest you trade for.
当然  没有肉  希望你们都是素食者
No meat of course. Hope you're vegetarian.
好吧
Oh yeah.
我们的目的地是加州的疾病控制中心研究所
We're headed to a CDC lab in California.
你们永远也到不了加利福尼亚
You're never gonna make it to California.
是啊  别人一直都这么对我说
Yeah, that's what I've been told.
不  我是认真的
No, seriously.
僵尸都群集在西部  数百万计的僵尸
The Zs are swarming out west. Millions of them.
我一直从别人或第三方消息来源那听说
Been hearing about it second and third hand.
城市里已被啃食得消失殆尽
Nothing left to eat in the city,
所以他们涌向旷野  形成超级僵尸群
so they're pouring into open country, forming mega herds.
谣传整个西海岸都是禁区
Rumor has it the whole west coast is a no-go zone.
我们还是要尝试一下
Well we still got to try.
那个人很讨厌
The guy's a pain in the ass,
但他是我们能被治愈的唯一机会
but he's our only chance for a cure.
如果你死了就什么也救不上了
Getting yourself killed won't cure anything.
我这早就需要你们了
I could use you here.
我需要训练有素的士兵和经验丰富的医生
I need experienced soldiers and a doctor.
这是个诱人的提议  乔
That's a tempting offer, Joe.
但是我们得继续前行
But we got to keep going.
我们时间紧迫
Clock's ticking on our guy.
实际上  我可以借助你的力量
In fact, I could use your help.
我们这一路上也需要像你这样的老派硬汉
We could use an old school ass kicker like you out on the road.
我也不知道  我看到过无数次希望破灭
I don't know. I've seen so much hope come to nothing.
这是我第一次投身于
This is the first thing I've been a part of
一个可行的事情里
that might actually work.
这些人依赖着我
These folks rely on me.
我知道
I know.
我明白了
I get it.
我有个备用房间  你们之中的两三个可以住进去
I've got a spare room two or three of you can use.
其他人就得在公共休息室睡了
The rest can grab a bunk in the community room.
让我考虑考虑你说的
Let me think about what you said.
我们明天再继续  你们也休息一下
We'll talk more tomorrow. In the meantime, get some rest.
谢谢
Thanks.
谢谢你
Thank you.
老兄  老兄  慢点  他们又不会拿走
Dude. Dude, slow down. They're not gonna take it from you.
所以
So...
我们摸清这的起居安排了
We got the lowdown on the sleeping situation.
有个房间  大家之中的两个或三个可以共住
There's a room that two or three of us can share,
并且这里还有公共休息室
and there's a communal bunk.
那个房间归老子了
Dibs on the room.
怎么了  这能减少他们弄清我身份的风险
What? Be less risk of anyone figuring out who I am.
我觉得我们应该把房间让给他俩
I think we should give it to those two.
什么  不不不  我们不是...
What, no, no, no. We're not a...
是啊  你们住吧
Yeah, you guys take it.
是啊
Yeah.
有这么明显吗
Is it that obvious?
好吧
Well...
如果我们能承受得起后果
If we're gonna do the time,
真去做点"坏事"又何妨呢
we may as well do the crime.
-你是认真的吗  -当然
- Are you serious? - Yes.
额  这可不太像我之前想的...
It's not exactly what I was...
这太完美了
It's perfect.
罗伯塔
Roberta, ummm...
怎么了
Yeah?
我是想说  快看
I mean, come on.
这间屋子  有张床
This room, it's like you know here's the bed.
它很...
It's...
舒适
cozy.
Cozy.
是啊
Yeah.
我不知道该说点什么
I don't know what to say.
什么也不要说
Don't say anything.
额  我身上没有...  那个
Hey, ummm, I don't have any...
我们会想出其他办法的
We'll think of something.
我上的是天主教学校[禁止婚外性行为]
I went to Catholic school.
这样啊
Oh.
椅子拿来
Chair.
对
All right.
你怕有修女进来吗
What are you worried about the nuns?
谁知道呢
Never know.
因为有福音传给我们
For indeed we have had good news preached to us,
正如传给非信徒一样
just as the unbelievers.
只是他们所闻之道于他们无益
But the word they heard did not profit them,
因为他们已将事实拒于心门之外
for their hearts were closed to the truth.
所以我们
So then we
要帮他们看清事实
shall open their eyes.
那家伙才被赶出去
That fella seems pretty popular
一回来就这么受欢迎啊
for a guy who just got kicked out of here.
那边的日子没想象中好过
It was a lot harder than we expected it.
所以我想着还是回来好了
Thought we'd be better off back here.
少校允许你回来  你挺幸运的
Lucky for you the Major was willing to take you in again.
是啊  我们都很幸运
Yes, it was lucky for us all.
嘿  卢克  你回来了呀
Hey, Luke. Glad to see you back, man.
我知道你不会蠢到相信那个雅各布小丑的
I knew you were too smart to fall for that Jacob clown.
是啊
Yeah.
去了之后发现跟我想的完全不一样
It wasn't at all what I thought it was gonna be.
很高兴我能回来
Glad to be back.
我好像把一些药落在弹药包里了
I think I left some meds in my ammo bag.
你能帮我找找吗
Do you mind checking for me?
没问题  等等
Sure, hang on.
嘿  你没事吧
Hey, are you all right?
所有人  都听着
Listen to me, all of you,
我有好消息要告诉你们
for I have good news.
少校不相信雅各布的善言
The major didn't believe in the word of Jacob.
但他以后会的
But he will.
你们还有一次机会聆听雅各布的善言
All of you will be given another chance to hear his word
加入重生教堂
and join the Resurrection Church.
你干什么  给我下来
What are you doing? Get down from there.
他身上有武器
He's got a weapon!
父怎样叫死人起来  使他们活着
For as the Father raises the dead and gives them life,
子也照样随自己的意思使人活着
so also the Son gives life to whom he will.
他要变异了
He's gonna turn.
该死
Damn it.
天哪  卢克
Oh God! Luke!
帮我关好门  不能放僵尸进去
Help me secure these doors! We have to contain this!
你确定你没上过天主教学校吗
Are you sure you didn't go to Catholic school?
嗯哼  走开
Uh-uh. Go away!
喂  关键时刻别来打扰我们
Hey! This is a very bad time to bother us.
哦  很不是时候哦
Oh, terrible time.
谁在外面
Who's there?
僵尸
Zombies?
不会的
It can't be.
摩菲
Murphy!
摩菲  快点
Murphy! Come on!
快来啊
Come on!
快来  走吧  快啊
Come on! Let's go! Hurry!
我现在只想要我的僵尸重击锤
I would give my left nut for that z-whacker right now!
大家快点啊
Come on, you guys!
快跑
Let's go!
这个太可怕了
Oh, that was a bad one.
摩菲哪儿去了
Where's Murphy?
我最后只看到他从别的门跑出去了
The last we saw, he ran out some other door.
要拿皮带把那家伙拴住才行
We need a leash for that guy.
有人把门撬开放僵尸进来了
Someone wedged that door open for the zombies.
什么
What?
我们一次干掉一只都费劲
We can barely face these guys one at a time.
这次爆发扩散了  会有五十只一起冲来
This outbreak spreads, they'll be coming at us 50 at a time.
摩菲和其他人怎么办
What about Murphy and the others?
我也不知道  我们需要武器
I don't know. We need weapons.
乔
Joe.
怎么回事
What the hell happened?
是雅各布和他的信徒
Jacob and his cult.
我们重新接收回来的那几个人切开了自己的喉咙
The ones we let back in slit their throats.
该死的  自杀变成了僵尸
Goddamn suicide zombies.
是他们阴谋破坏了那些门
They sabotaged the doors.
混账疯子
Insane bastards.
我们努力做的一切已经没了  都没了
Everything we've worked for, it's gone. All gone.
我们需要武器
We need weapons.
武器库已经全是僵尸了  我们进不去
The armory's full of Zs. We can't get in there.
肯定还有被你藏起来的
Well you got to have some hidden somewhere.
没有  都在笼子里
No. They're all in the cage.
全部吗
All of them?!
那我们怎么自卫
How are we supposed to defend ourselves?!
我以为没有僵尸能进的来
I thought we were zombie-proofed!
听着  乔
Hey, Joe.
你不能崩溃  伙计
You got to pull yourself together, man.
肯定有办法出去
There's got to be a way out of here.
加内特
Garnett!
感谢上帝你没事
Thank God you're okay.
摩菲呢
Where's Murphy?
我们走散了  到处都是僵尸
Got separated. Zombies everywhere.
一万呢
10K?
他也不见了
He's out there somewhere.
他能保护自己
If anyone can make it he can.
那要有枪才行
If only he had his gun.
在我们完全沦陷之前
You have to get to the emergency exit
你们必须到紧急出口去
before we're completely overrun.
出口在哪
Where is it?
穿过那些门
Through those doors.
长长的走廊尽头有一个加固门
There's a long hallway ending in a reinforced door.
出去就能到外面了
It leads outside the perimeter.
然后一直跑到树林那边不要停
Don't stop till you hit the woods,
然后你们就可以折回到你们的卡车那了
then you can double back around to your truck.
那你怎么办
What about you?
我要留在这  尽我所能地救人
I've got to stay and try to save as many as I can.
准备好了吗
Ready?
好了
Indeed.
很好  出发
All right, let's go!
杀了你  该死的僵尸
Die you freakin' Z!
我是人  我是人  我是人
Human! Human. Human.
抱歉  你看起来好像僵尸
Sorry. You look like one of them.
你自己脸色也不太好  亲爱的
You don't look so good yourself, sweetheart.
听着  我需要帮助
Look, I need some help.
好  我们一起行动  两个人机会更大
Okay. We'll stick together. Two of us might have a chance.
你怎么不帮忙
Why didn't you help?
僵尸怎么不攻击你
Why didn't it attack you?
是不是你的阴谋
Are you part of this?!
不  不
No! No.
救命  看在上帝的份上
Help me! For God's sake!
不要走
Don't leave me!
来吧  兄弟姐妹们  我预言过的
Come, brothers and sisters! It is as I foretold!
基督再临就在此处
Our Second Coming is here!
看吧  重生者
Behold the Resurrected!
是时候得到属于我们的东西了
It's time to take what is rightfully ours.
活捉亵渎神明的人
Bring me the Blasphemers alive.
死路  打不开
It's jammed! It won't open!
回去  回去
Turn around! Turn around!
退后  门堵上了
Back up! The door's blocked!
大家  我们难逃一劫的
Guys, we're not gonna make it.
我们得转过身
We have to turn around!
退回去
Go back!
快点
Come on!
查理  我很害怕
Charlie, I'm scared.
把那些僵尸推回去
Push those Zs back!
我甚至没法转过身
I can't even turn around.
推
Push!
艾迪  艾迪  艾迪
Addy! Addy! Addy!
坚持住  艾迪  过来这里
Stay with me! Addy! Come here.
喂喂  没事的
Hey, hey. It's okay.
我们撑不了多久了
We're not gonna last much longer.
一万
10k!
快点  快点
Come on. Come on.
我们要怎样离开这里
How do we get out of here?
我只能在屋顶上走动
I've been using the roofs to move.
那群狂热信徒在楼里  持械
The cult freaks are in the compound. Armed.
摩菲呢
Murphy?
没看到他
Haven't seen him.
我们需要武器
We need weapons.
然后再去找摩菲  行动
Then we'll find Murphy. Let's go.
兄弟姐妹们好
Greetings brothers and sisters.
重生教堂欢迎你
The Resurrection Church welcomes you.
请把双手举高
Please raise your hands to the heavens
否则我就地让你们重生
or I will resurrect you where you stand.
让他们走
Let them go.
重生者会处理他们的
The Resurrected will take care of them.
留下的人跟我们走
The rest of you, come with us.
最后一批重生者已经被控制了
The last of the Resurrected have been secured.
而那些在今天逝去的人们
And those who died today have the honor
有幸比我们早一步接受上帝的恩典
of entering into grace ahead of us.
上帝保佑他们一路走来
Blessed is the path before them.
上帝保佑他们前路平安
Blessed will their journey be.
兄弟姐妹们
Brothers and sisters,
我知道现在你们的内心是憎恨的
I know you have hate in your hearts right now
不愿意站出来接受信仰的考验
and do not come willingly to this test of faith.
但今天你们每个人都会成为
But today each of you will become part
新重生者教堂的一份子
of the New Resurrection Church.
不管怎样你们得先选择要怎么服务
First however you must choose how you will serve.
你们可以加入生者的队伍
You may join the living flock
在活着的每一天为重生者服务
and spend your days serving the Resurrected.
或者选择让你们的灵魂继续
Or your souls taking the next step on their journey
它的永生
to eternal life.
现在是你们做出选择的时候了
The time has come for you to choose.
加入我和生者一起走下去
Join me and walk among the living
或者追随这个
or follow this blasphemer
以为可以与正义为敌
who thought he could oppose the righteous
却成了行尸走肉的亵渎者
and now walks among the dead.
现在不要为少校感到悲伤  兄弟姐妹们
Now don't feel sorrow for the Major, brothers and sisters.
虽然我们不喜欢以前的他
Although we stood against the man he was,
我们要为他选择加入重生者感到高兴
we take joy in his choice to join the Resurrected!
上帝保佑他一路走来
Blessed is the path before him!
什么选择
What choice?
跟你这种疯子一起生活  或死后成为僵尸
To live with you lunatics or die and become a zombie?
我不知道你的名字  兄弟
I don't know your name, brother.
但我欢迎你来到重生教堂
But I welcome you to the Resurrection Church.
跟我们在一起你会得到永恒的快乐和安宁
With us you will know everlasting joy and peace.
以前这里很安宁
There was peace here.
被你杀死的乔·威廉姆斯  给过你安宁
Joe Williams, the man you killed, gave you peace.
这里以前很好  这里以前很安全
This was a good place. This was a safe place.
这里可以恢复安宁
And it can be again.
现在还为时不晚  放下武器
It's not too late. Put down your weapons.
让我们过人道的生活
Let's live the way that people are supposed to.
互相帮助  一起工作  现在还来得及
Helping one another, working together. It's not too late.
放下武器  释放我们  我们会帮助你们
Put down your weapons. Let us free. We'll help you.
你我相比于那些重生者要更接近上帝
The Resurrected aren't any closer to God than you and I are.
我真嫉妒你  兄弟
I envy you, brother.
你即将迈入重生者的行列
The time for you to walk among the Resurrected is near.
查理
Charlie.
我要杀了你  你这个神棍
I'm gonna kill you, you psychotic bastard.
别担心  小姐妹
Don't you worry, sister.
你很快就会步上你宝贝查理的后尘
You won't be far behind your Charlie.
快射他
Shoot him.
我没法瞄准
I can't get a shot.
我得去屋顶
I need to get on the roof.
你去把卡车开过来
You get the truck.
你们俩都会先我一步获得永生
Rejoice as both of you will walk before me
我真为你俩高兴
on the road to everlasting life.
听着  雅各布
Listen, Jacob.
你可以杀了我  让我重生
Kill me, resurrect me,
但是你要放了其他人
but spare the others.
别怕  兄弟
Don't be afraid, brother.
我是在送你去更棒的地方
I send you to a better place.
他面前就是神明庇佑之路
Blessed is the path before him!
我就是耶稣复活在世  生命之神
I am the new Resurrection and the life.
信我者  虽死犹生
Whoever believes in me, though he die, yet shall he live.
够了
Stop!
要是你们认为重生者更接近天堂
If you think the Resurrected are one step closer to heaven
那就准备好迎接你们的新上帝吧
then prepare to meet your new god.
快来  兄弟
Come, brother.
快从重生者堆里出来
Step away from the Resurrected.
凡人不该待在那里
That's no place for a mortal human.
快来加入我们  这里欢迎所有凡人
Come join our flock. All are welcome.
加入你们吗
Join your flock?
我不是重生者之一
I am not one of the Resurrected.
我才是你们的救世主
I'm your Messiah.
你这是在亵渎神明  兄弟
That's blasphemy, brother.
大家都看得出你就是一介凡人而已
We can all see you're one of the living.
八次
Eight times!
我被咬过八次
I was bitten
但是我并没有变成僵尸
and did not turn!
我被僵尸那血淋淋的唾液感染过八次
Eight times I was infected by their bloody saliva.
但如今我完好无损站你们面前
And yet here I stand before you.
我想要告诉你们
And I am here to tell you that he
他就是个假先知
is a false prophet!
因为我才是真正的耶稣复活在世
For I am the true incarnation of the Resurrected!
他到底在做什么
What the hell is he doing?
我也搞不清楚
I have no idea.
把这个渎神者干掉
Kill the blasphemer.
但是他身上那些咬痕  雅各布
But the bites, Jacob.
他是个假先知
He's a false prophet!
我能够证明
I can prove it!
我能够证明我所言不假
I can prove that my words are true.
那说来听听吧  渎神者
Tell us, blasphemer.
这个弥天大谎你还想要怎么圆
How can you possibly prove this outrageous lie?
我会证明给你看
I'll show you.
好好看着吧  你们这群怀疑论者
Observe Ye of little faith.
天呐[耶稣]
Jesus.
不是  就是摩菲而已
No. Just Murphy.
好  这样就够了
Okay, that's enough of that.
重生者不会攻击我
The Resurrected will not attack me
因为他们爱我敬我
because they love and fear me.
大家好好看清楚
Behold my flock.
这就是你们要的证据  兄弟姐妹们
There's your proof, brothers and sisters!
放我们走  雅各布
Now let us go, Jacob,
不然我们的人会让你们全部复活
before my flock resurrects all of you!
雅各布  如果他说的是事实怎么办
Jacob, what if he's speaking the truth?
他不是救世主  我会证明这一点
He's no messiah. I'll prove it.
你还要通过最后一个测试  亵渎神明的人
There's one last test for you to pass, blasphemer.
见鬼
Damn it.
一颗穿心的子弹即可揭示真相
A bullet to the heart will reveal the truth!
不要
No!
查理
Charlie.
你不会有事的
You'll be ok.
去救  去救摩菲
Go get... Go get Murphy.
不  我不会离开你
No. I'm not leaving you.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
那就走
Then go.
活下去
Live.
不
No.
别
Don't.
别走
Don't go.
快点
Come on!
沃伦  我们得走了
Warren, we have to go.
-不  -我们得马上走
- No. - We have to go now!
我们不能让他变异
We can't let him turn!
不  我们必须对他"施以仁慈"
No! We have to give him mercy!
没有时间了
There's no time!
不  让我去
No! Let me go!
不行  等一下
No! Wait a minute!
没有时间了
There's no time.
不  不要  等一下
No. No. Wait!
等一下
Wait!
快点  快点  快点
Come on. Come on. Come on.
我们得走了  一万
We have to go, 10K!
她在干什么
What is she doing?
查尔斯·加内特
Charles Garnett,
我仁慈地结束你的生命
I give you mercy.
我们走吧
Let's go.
也许有一天我们会发现
Someday maybe we'll find out
僵尸灾变发生的真正原因
the real reason the Zombie Apocalypse happened.
所有的死亡和毁灭  所有的痛苦和悲伤
All this death and destruction. All the pain and heartache.
我们可以怪责谁
Who do we blame?
也许是政府实验室的病毒出逃
Maybe it was a government virus that escaped the lab.
也许是巫毒
Maybe it was voodoo.
或者也许只是上帝看我们不顺眼
Or maybe God just doesn't like us.
但有时候
Some days though
我会想这是不是我们咎由自取
I wonder if we brought this on ourselves.
我们有过机会用正确的方式对待这个星球
We had a chance to do this whole planet earth thing right, and...
而我们搞砸了
and we blew it.
这个世界末日是我们罪有应得
We got the Apocalypse we deserved.
但如果我们运气好
But if we're lucky,
某一天这一切终将结束
some day this will all be over.
我希望如此
I hope so.
但下一次  我希望我们别再做错
And next time, I hope we get it right.